Mark.Mark!
Mark Mark!
Mark 问问你爸爸要不要汉堡?
Mark, would you pleaseask your father if he wants a burger?
我知道你在保卫自由世界,问你爸要不要汉堡
I know, you're defendingthe free world.Please ask your dadif he wants a burger.
爸
Dad.
dad.
妈妈问你要不要汉堡
Mom wants to knowif you want a burger.
妈 我问不出来
Mom, I don't knowwhat he wants.
要汉堡吗?
You want a burger?
自己驾驶轮椅驶入泳池 House会喜欢的
the guy drove his wheelchairinto a pool.House would love that.
没意思的 场面够刺激,但诊断起来很无趣
He'll be bored.It's a great visual,but it's diagnostically boring.
植发后发生失语症的?
What about post-hair-transplantaphasia guy?
感染导致血管栓塞,House肯定不接 还会骂你白痴
Infection throwing clots.House'll shoot it downand call you an idiot.
我不想被他骂
Oh, well,I wouldn't want that.
做瑜伽的女孩?
What about yoga girl?
好像有点意思
It has a good hook.
就给他这个病例吧?
Should we lead with it?
回来上班第一天 他需要舒展毒舌
His first day backhe might want to flex his sarcasm muscle.
先给他一个简单的吧
Maybe we open with one of the weaker pitches.
你跑来的?
You ran here?
8英里而已
It's just eight miles.
为什么你--
Why did you--
为什么狗会舔[睾丸的代替语]?
why does a dog lick its workplace-acceptable euphemismfor testicles?
因为能舔到
Because he can.
有什么病人 老板?
What do you gotfor me, boss?
按照8周康复时间 你早该来了
I thought you said you neededeight weeks of rehab.You should'vebeen back here--
那时我只能跑6英里 到不了这里
if I'd come back sooner, then I'd only be ableto run six miles.I never would've made it in.
什么病人?
What do you got for me?
你现在不疼了?
You're completelypain-free?
K他命的效果应该退了
The ketamine treatmentcan wear off.
两个月了 还没有退
It's been two months.It's not wearing off.
什么病人?
What do you gotfor me?
- 效果能持续...- 谈这个做什么?
-It can takeas long as--,-why are we havingthis discussion?
想让我再次感谢你? 谢谢 Cuddy医生
Nna hear me ank you again?Thank you, dr.Cuddy--
不仅为取子弹
not justfor removing the bullet,
而且把我置于k他命诱发的昏迷,改变了我的人生
but thank you for putting me in a ketamine-induced coma and changing my life.
高兴吗? 确实
Happy?I am.
中年男子两个月前植发
Middle-aged manhad a hair transplant about two months ago--
感染导致血管栓塞 你是个白痴
infection throwing clots.You're an idiot.
看来你不是白痴
Except you're not an idiot.
她手里的是个26岁女性
And she's holding a filefor a 26-year-old female.
到底给我哪个?
What do you really gotfor me?
女孩子做一个瑜伽倒立姿势,脖子挫伤 颈部下瘫痪
Girl was doingan inverted yoga pose.Neck snapped.Paralyzed from the neck down.
但是X光未发现脊椎损伤
Except the x-rays showno evidence of spinal injury.
她很可爱
And she's cute.
做的好 先生
Oh, well played, sir.
想以自己微薄的力量,掀起蝴蝶效应的史蒂芬霍金
What about stephen hawkingtrying to do the 500 butterfly?
算了吧 脑癌 外科手术
Forget it.Brain cancer, brain surgery.
没什么好诊的了 要我就挑另一个
There's nothing left diagnose.I would takethe other one.
我两个都要
I'll take 'em both.
你以为他不是脑癌
You don't thinkhe had brain cancer?
当然有脑癌 即使你们肿瘤科,也不会坏到折磨病人8年
Course he had brain cancer.Even oncologists don't screw upfor eight years.
没什么诊断疑问 为什么接这个病例
So if there's nodiagnostic issue, why are you takingthe case?
治疗很有趣
Treatment can be interesting.
- 对你来说不会,- 我变了
-Not to you.-I've changed.
- 你才不会变,- 我没变
-No, you haven'T.-No, I haven'T.
那为什么接这个
So why are you takingthe case?
想自杀的人
Guy tried to kill himselF.
他有癌症 半死不活的
The guy had cancer.He's a lump.
不能碰自己的妻子,不能跟孩子说话
He hasn't been ableto touch his wife, speak to his kids.
他做了8年轮椅
He's been in that chairfor eight years.
他的肌肉萎缩了,也许我可以帮他缓解疼痛
His muscles have atrophied.Maybe I can help himwith the pain.
想帮人 这样的理由还不充分?
Isn't that enough of a reasonto want to help?
你可不是
Not for you.
那为什么我接这个病例?
Then why am I takingthis case?
我们先看看漂亮的瘫痪者
Let's startwith the cute paraplegic.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
你看着...
You look--
很健康
healthy.
脖子没受伤却颈部以下瘫痪,很罕见
Quad with no broken neck.Struck me as odd.
先缓两分钟 不着急开始工作
Uh, you could takea whole two minutes to ease into being back.
我已经缓了一个月了
Wouldn't taken a whole monthto ease back.
腹部和颈部枪伤,8周康复时间已经够多了
But eight weeks isthe maximum rehab time for a gunshot woundto the stomach and neck.
开始吧
So go.
听说还没抓到那人 有新线索吗?
We heard they neverfound the guy.There's no new leads?
你担心他会给这个病人也来一枪?,这么解释她的症状就对了
What, you thinkhe might've shot this patient, too?That would explain her symptoms.
多发性硬化症
Could be M.S.
看 不是很难
See?It's not so difficult.
不是多发性硬化症
It's not M.S.
她在倒立之前并无症状
She had no symptoms beforeshe climbed onto her head.
除非她在过去10年里一直倒立,否则不是多发性硬化症
Unless she's been upside-downfor the last ten years, M.S.Ain't it.
可能是横贯性脊髓炎,椎盘肿胀 阻断神经功能
Could be transverse myelitis,swelling in the disks choking off nerve function.
核磁共振否定了
mri was negative for that.
(缺一句)
你的腿挺好的 完全不疼了?
怎么话题又转到,"你夏天做了什么" 这种闲话上了?
When did this turn into"what did you do over your summer vacation?
你盯着自己的血迹,这样谈病例好似很怪异
"it's a little weird to discuss the casewhile you're staring at your blood on the floor.
我跟Cuddy说过换掉地毯
I asked cuddyto replace the carpet.
我喜欢这地毯
I like the carpet.
你夏天做了什么?
What did you doover the summer?
- 我,- 再检查一遍
-I--,-redo the tests.
看看问题出在四肢还是脊柱,做个脑电图
Let's see if the sourceof the problem is in the limbsor the spine.Do an emg.
这里还有个颈部以下瘫痪的
Got a whole other quadto cover.
肺部还有积液
This guy's still got fluid in his lungs.
会不会是掉落泳池导致的?
You don't think that'sfrom the pool he drank?
给他吸氧 他的腿部肌肉萎缩了
Get him an o-2 mask.His leg muscleshave atrophied.
肌腱由于长期不用会变短,导致剧痛
Tendons have shortened from disuse, causing intense pain.
肌腱手术可以让他好过些
Tendon surgery will make himmore comfortable.
好过?
comfortable?
赶紧
Scoot.
谢谢你在这里
anks for being here.
不客气
not a problem.
我爸不会自杀
My dad wouldn't kill himself.
你6年没跟他说话了
You haven't spoken to himin over six years.
我了解我爸
I know my dad.
Mark 医生只是想...
Mark, the doctor'sjust trying to--
他不会自杀
he wouldn't kill himself.
好吧 我错了
Fine.I'm wrong.
显然你很了解这个一天到晚,嘴角流涎的人
You obviously havea better understanding of this man who drooin front of your tv set 24 hours a day.
House医生
Dr.House.
他一定是搞错了
he must have been confused.
知道吗? 肯定是意外
All right?It must have beenan accident.
我希望他是自杀
Hope it wasa suicide attempt.
如果他想自杀,说明他知道生不如死
If he was trying to kill himself, then he knows how miserable his life is.
说明他仍是一条生命
It means there's stillsomething there to kill.
他还在你们身边
It means your dad'sstill there.
对不起 来一下
Sorry.Need you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们在做脑电图,插导电针的时候出了状况
We were doing the emg,but we never got past the insertionof the conduction pin.
她刚才说谢谢?
Did she just say"thank you"?
我借钱给她 哪里出错了?
I loaned her some money.What went wrong?
没出错
Nothing went wrong.
如果没出错 就应该做对
If nothing went wrong,then something went right.
你不说她为什么感谢你?
You're not gonna tell mewhy she thanked you?
你不说做对了什么?
You're not gonna tell mewhat went right?
你为她做了些事 她感谢你,这让你...
You did somethingfor which she is grateful, and you're...
窘迫?
embarrassed?
因为你
For you.
她看你走上来 以为你是个14岁小男生,我纠正了她
She saw you coming up, thought you werea 14-year-old boy.I set her straight.
我不告诉你出了什么问题,或做对了什么
I am not telling youwhat went wrong.Or right.
除非你告诉我她为什么谢你
Until you tell mewhy she said thank you.
抓住我弱点了
Oh, you've got me.
你知道我很想知道 我一定认输
You know I need to know.I am so gonna fold.
但你不知道我还有一招
Except you're forgettingthere's one thing I can do now.
这个 或者是神经反射的问题
It's either thator a reflex response or--
怎么了?
what happened?
好吧
Okay.
这是House医生
This is dr.House.
- House 这位是Caren,- 荣幸之至 怎么了?
-House, this is caren.-Pleasure's all mine.What happened?
当我们插入导电针 她抖动了
When we insertedthe conduction pin,she flinched.
她动了! 听见了?
She flinched!Did you hear?
是不是意味着好转了
Does that mean I'm getting better?
抖了多大一下
How big is a flinch?
比抽动大 比痉挛小?
Bigger than a twitch?Smaller than a spasm?
你抽烟吗?
You smoke?
应酬型的 抽的不多
Socially.Not a lot.
你做瑜珈 还抽烟?
You do yogaand you smoke?
我知道 我是两面人
I know.It's hypocritical.
没关系 大家都在看你的腿
Not at all.The world sees your legs.
没人检查你的肺
No one's checking out your lungs.
- 吸烟怎么会导致...- 不会
-How would smoking--,-it wouldn'T.
我只是找火机
I just needed a lighter.
House!
我的天
Oh, my god!
症状很像那么回事
The case was lookingso promising.
我不是假装的
Hey, I'm not faking.
你动了 说明你没瘫
You moved.Therefore, you can move.
趁早把这个疯子弄出去吧
Get this lunaticout of here before she bores again.
我不是假装的
I'm not faking!
我听说你刚才跟病人家属一起看手术
I heard youwere watching surgery with a patient's family.
还跟病人家属谈话了
Talking to a patient's family.
是你的幻觉影响了你吧?,被枪击后的阴影
It's because of yourhallucination, isn't it?After you were shot.
你重新选择生活 选你想要的生活
You chose life.You decidedyou wanted meaning.
所以你挑了个没什么挑战性的病例
So you took a casewith no mystery.
任何医生都会治的那种
Something any doctor could do.
除了可以治好那个病人,这病例并没有什么突破性
A case with no upside except the satisfaction of helpinganother human being.
她感谢我
She thanked me.
但是 你感觉不到什么
And...you felt nothing.
我也不知道应该有什么感觉
I wasn't even surewhat I was supposed to feel.
这就跟你的腿一样 它萎缩了
It's like your leg.It's atrophied.
多试几次 感觉就回找回来的
Keep working it.The feeling will come.
不好意思
Sorry.
还是要你来
Need you.Again.
我说了赶她走
I told youto get rid of her.
还好没赶走 她胸部受到压迫
It's a good thing we didn'T.Tightness in her chest.
呼吸困难 可能有胸膜渗出液
She can't breathe.It could bea pleural effusion.
恩
Right.
不然的话她就是故意像小朋友一样屏气
Either thator she's holding her breath like a four-year-old.
放松点
RelaX.
我不会再烧你了
I'm not gonnaburn you again.
我要戳你!
I'm going to stab you!
听着 如果你不是假装的话,就是有胸膜渗出液了
Look, either you're faking or you've gota pleural effusion.
是由肺周围的体液形成的 这很严重
That's a buildup of fluidaround the lungs,which is very serious,
我只能用这个针头戳进你的背,把它们吸出来
and I'd have no choice but to stab you in the backwith this needle and suck all the fluidout of you.
-所以,- 应该做局麻
-So.-we should give her a local.
那跟我恶劣的形象就不相符了
That would defeat the pointof me being nasty.
准备好了?
Ready?
-躺下,-她躺下就不能呼吸了
-Down.-She can't breathe if she's down.
-躺下,-她不能...
-Down.-She can't--
快 快 快!让她躺下!
down, down, down!Come on!
那不是胸膜渗出液
That's nota pleural effusion.
是她心脏有问题
The problem's in her heart.
这是装不出来的
Can't fake that.
过去两小时我已经三次给她减压了
I've had to relievethe pressure three times In the last two hours.
要么我们就查清楚心脏周围出血的原因
So either we figure out what's causing blood to build uparound her heart,
要么我就拿着针头追着她整个下半辈子
or I follow her aroundwith a needle for the rest of her life.
没有心脏杂音 也没有器质性病变
Echo was clean.No structural abnormalities.
可能是个感染的过程 比如结核
Could be aninfectious process, tb.
或者系统性血管炎 这可以解释渗出液
Or vasculitis would alsoplain the effusion.
但是不能解释她双脚的瘫痪
but not the paralysis.
我们假设她不是装的
Let's assumethat she wasn't faking it.
她动了 就是说 她可以活动
she moved.Therefore, she could move.
她没有瘫痪
She wasn't paralyzed.
那不一定是装的 可能是一种错觉
Doesn't mean she was faking.Could have been a delusion.
也可能她是装的
Either she was faking
碰巧她有心脏病 在同一时间发作,或者仍然是错觉
and coincidentallygot a real cardiac problem at the exact same time, or it's a delusion.
这种瘫痪的假象是种神经学症状
And the fake paralysisis a real neurological symptom.
你认为她脊柱里有血管瘤?
You thinking vascular tumorin her spine?
她的血小板数正常
Her platelets are normal.
她全身上下都扫描过了 没发现什么
And she's been scannedup and down.It was all clean.
那就打开她身体去找
So open her up and find it.
你想让我们做什么?
so what do you want us to do?
从颈部开始一节节脊椎找 直到发现异物?
Start at her neck and just keep cuttingdown her spine until we stumble on something?
应该行得通的
That should work.
心率偏高
His heart rate'sa little high.
很严重吗?
Should I be worried?
可能他只是还没有从手术从恢复过来
Probably just meanshe's still in discomfort from the surgery.
我会调高他的吗啡用量
I'm gonna up his morphinea little.
你对我们真好
You've been so nice to us.
这是医生该做的
That's the job.
不 我的意思是 其他的医生
No, I mean,all the other doctors,
他们只关心病情 治疗方案 损伤情况
all they did was obsess on the cancer, the treatment, the damage.
只是为了救他
Just trying to fix him.
你是第一个真正关心他的生命质量的医生
You're the first doctor that's ever given a damnabout the quality of his life.
他的心率下来了
His heart rate'scome down.
吗啡起作用了 我做对了
Morphine worked.I was right.
真是感人的一幕
What a touching moment.
这就是我们做医生的原因
That's whywe become doctors.
一个这样的场面就能让我们倍感温暖
One of those rare momentswhen our hearts are warmed--
想喝点什么吗?
would you liketo get a drink?
你是说真的 还是只想换个话题?
Are you serious, or are you just tryingto change the subject?
不是 我说真的
No, I'm serious.
我喝 你也喝
I drink.You drink.
我们可以一起喝
We could do itat the same time.
坐同一张桌子
At the same table.
想吃点什么吗?
Do you eat?
我们也可以一起进餐啊
We could do that, too.
我是说 如果你不想 那也可以 不过...
I mean, if the answer is no, that's cool, but--
不是的 只是...
no, it's just--
你刚做完手术 还没有完全恢复
you're just comingoff the surgery, and you're not yourself yet.
我是你的下属 尽管去年...
And I work for you,and even though last year'S...
你在笑 我拒绝你 你却在笑
You're smiling.I'm saying no,and you're smiling.
我可不是针对你
Oh, don't take itpersonally.
而是因为你满嘴的胡说八道
It's just 'causeyou're full of crap.
你根本不想跟我约会
You have no interestin going out with me.
也许你想过...
Maybe you did...
在我不能走的时候
when I couldn't walk.
我是个生病的可怜虫,你可以让我恢复健康
When I was a sick puppy that you could nurtureback to health.
现在我好了 你就没有兴趣了
Now that I'm healthy,there's nothing in it for you.
你并没有好
You are not healY.
Cuddy要见你
Cuddy wants to see you.
你才恢复工作24小时就开始在一个女人,的脊柱里玩躲迷藏的把戏了
You've been back at work24 hours, and you're alreadyplaying hide-and-seek in a woman's spine.
谁赌赢了?
Who won the pool?
没有发现肿瘤
There's no tumor.
她的血小板数也正常
Her platelets are normal.
- 扫描也没发现...- 情况最坏会怎样?
-The scans didn't--,-what's the worstthat can happen?
我令她瘫痪
I paralyze her.
她甚至都注意不到
She wouldn't even notice.
她的律师会的
Her lawyers might.
这个手术不能做,你另一个病人的吗啡剂量要降下来
You're not doing the surgery.And lower the morphineon your other patient.
好吧 我降,如果你让我坐手术
Fine, I'll lower it.If you'll let me dothe surgery.
什么?
What?
这是做交换?
You want to trade?
咱们是农夫吗?,你帮我堆草 我送你山羊?
We're not swappin'a couple of goats for your helpputtin' up a barn.
你有所求 我也有所求
You want something.I want something.
咱们妥协 这是处理冲突的理智方式
We compromise.It's the grownup wayto resolve our differences.
我们对此有成熟的机制
There alreadyis a mechanism for that.
叫做上下级关系
It's called the employer-employee relationship.
我可以得到我想要的,你不能
I get what I want,and you don'T.
你想交换?
You tried to swap?
做几项检查
Ran a few more tests.
如果没异常就做手术
Came back negative.Surgery's on.
你真的不在乎 是吧?
You really don'tgive a crap, do you?
这么说我是坏蛋?
Does that make me evil?
没错
Yeah.
女孩的生命危在旦夕,我们还在谈论...
The girl's lifeis at stake.All we're talking aboutwith the guy is--
我们在谈论的是你接下病例的原因
all we're talking aboutis the reason you took the case.To help someone.
- 算他们倒霉,- 算你倒霉
-Too bad for them.-Too bad for you.
我们渴望有意义,因为这让我们快乐
The reason we crave meaning is becauseit makes us happy.
快乐的第一个层面是...
The first levelof happiness is--
我不会走开
I'm not going away.
快乐的第五个层面是创造
the fifth level of happiness involves creation.
改变生活
Changing lives.
快乐的第六个层面是海洛因,第七是你走远点
the sixth level is heroin.The seventh level is you going away.
你在拯救生命 这几乎等于创造生命
You're saving lives.Which is tantamountto creating lives.
但是你只要把它当一个游戏
But all you're takingaway from this is the game.
你不用听别人感谢你
You don't have to listen to them thanking you.
你不用改变接病例的习惯,或者诊治的方式
You don't have to change the cases you take or even how you handle them.
只需知道你的努力有成效
You just have to know that you made a difference.
House 你不是--
House, you're not--
我可不是傻子
I'm not an idiot.
House 别碰她
house, leave her alone.
把手术停了
close her up.
想知道为什么?
Wanna know why?
手术室不再是无菌的了
The room's no longer sterile.
没错 但那不是最有意思的原因
True, but that's notthe most interesting reason.
那可不是一个性感的大脚趾
That is not a sexy big toe.
你才不会不会把那放进嘴里
You would neverput that in your mouth.
- 那到底是怎么回事--,- 说了有意思
-What the hellhas that got to do with--,-told youit was interesting.
甚至会很有意思
It gets even better.
坏血病?
Scurvy?
嗯 喝吧
Yeah.Drink.
出海的水手饮食单调得的病?
Like what sailors getwhen they don't eat right?
是的
Aye-aye.
你的臂部和腿部组织都淤了血
Your arms and leg tissuesare choked with blood.
因此你动弹不得,还损坏了你的头发和脚趾甲
Makes it hard to move.Also damages your hairand toenails.
但是我正在节食,大量的蛋白质 大量的--
But I'm on this great diet.Lots of protein, lots of--
没有维生素C
no vitamin C.
现在喝了它
Now drink.
嗯 谢谢你
Well, thank you.
还要谢谢 House 医生
And thank dr.House.
给他写个纸条吧
Send him a note.
护士改变了他的吗啡用量,我想你是担心他--
The nurse changedhis morphine.I thought you wereworried about the--
仅仅是术后不适症状 他可以回家了
it's just post-opdiscomfort.He's ready to go home.
所以他不再会感到疼痛吗?
So he won't haveany pain?
最终不会
Eventually.
谢谢你了
Thank you.
别的事也会这样
Everything elsewill be the same.
你祛除了他的疼痛 那--,已经改变了很多
Well, you took away his pain,and that--that changes a lot.
为什么不送他去那些看护中心呢?
Why don't you put himin some sort of facility?
没有泳池的地方
Someplace without a pool.
是啊 我可以把他扔在那儿
Yeah, I could dump him there.
可是
Except...
他是我的丈夫
he's my husband.
是我儿子的父亲
He's my son's father.
没错
Right.
孩子们需要爸爸
Kids need a dad.
可以互相追着玩 可以一起讨论女孩
Someone to play catch with,talk about girls.
Mark 已经明白了不需要抛弃别人--
Mark's learned that you don'thave to abandon someone--
养只小狗吧
get a dog.
我会好好照顾他的 正如你帮了我们
I'm taking care of him for the same reasonyou helped us.
有人朝你开枪了? 你也有幻觉?
Some guy shot you,and you hallucinated?
我有这个责任
I have a responsibility.
他是一个沉重的铁锚,会带着你和你家人一起往下坠
So he's just an anchor weighingyou and your family down.
消耗你的精力 浪费你的生命,那是你获得的生命意义
Sapping your energy,wasting your life.That's the meaningyou take from this.
我想好好照顾他
I want to take care of him.
你乐在其中
You enjoy this.
我不能抛弃他
I can't abandon him.
所以你本不想照顾他
So you don't wantto take care of him.
照顾他不能让你感到满足 让你开心
Taking care of him doesn't fulfill you,make you happy.
但是不照顾他你会很痛苦
But not taking care of himwould make you miserable.
好了
Okay.
我们走
Here we go.
我不需要你的帮助 我已经做过无数次了
I don't need your help.I've done thisa million times.
让他背朝下躺下
Lay him back down.
再做一次
Do that again.
发出那个声音
Make that sound.
那是什么?
What was that?
那...
That...
是在说话
was talking.
你们这群无能的医生
you guysare lousy doctors.
一个个都忙着让病人好受点,却忘了查出到底是什么病因
You're in such a rush to make the patient feel better, you forgot to checkwhat was wrong.
瑜珈女孩2小时前走着离开医院,你治好了她
Yoga girl walked out of heretwo hours ago.You fixed her.
不是她 是别人
Not her.The other guy.
他患了脑瘤 8年前切除了
He had brain canceR.They removed iteight years ago.
从那时起他的状况就一直这样
His condition's been the sameever since.
直到昨晚 他说话了
Until last night.He spoke.
他说什么了?
What'd he say?
他...只发出了咕噜声?
He...grunted?
你要我们把8年来所有有咕噜症状,的病人仔细研究一遍?
You want us to dissect eight years of medical historywith grunting in the differential?
看来不错 做好了叫我
Sounds good.Call me when you're done.
你很无聊地捏造了一个秘密
You're fabricating a mysterybecause you're bored.
我才不无聊呢
I am not bored.
该死
Damn it.
你不会告诉他妻子那只是个咕噜声吧?
You didn't tell the wifeit was only a grunt?
当然不会
Of course not.
否则她就不会同意做一连串危险的检查了
Because then she neverwould have consented to a bunch of dangerous tests.
你几时这么爱管闲事了
I don't remember youbeing this bitchy.
维柯丁(止痛药)让你行动迟钝,在白天清醒的光芒下 我是乐趣杀手
The vicodin dulled it.In the sober light of day,I'm a buzz-kill.
你给一个可怜的家庭虚假的希望
You're giving false hope to a family that's been wrecked.
别再折磨他们了
Don't torture them.
随他去吧 告诉他妻子那只是一声咕噜,让她回家
Let it go.Tell the wifeit was only a grunt.Tell her to go home.
我不能看着她就这么绝望
I can't let her downlike that.
要用多多虚假的希望把她拉上来
Pumped her upwith too much false hope.
瞧 我做得多漂亮!
Oh, I stuck that primo!
我真是太出色了!
How rad am I?
2002年 病人患了干眼症
2002, patient had dry eyes.
干眼症并发咕噜
Dry eyes plus a grunt.
都可能是病因
It all makes sense.
也可能是神经问题
Could bea neurological issue.
我得花粉热 滴眼药水的时候,可不会去找神经科医生
I get hay fever,I put drops in my eyes.I don't goto a neurologist.
干眼症可能表明自主性神经官能障碍
Dry eyes could indicatean autonomic dysfunction.
写到白板上
Goes on the board.
会不会是咳嗽?
What about coughing?
或者是鼻屎?,不应该把鼻屎也包括进来吗?
Or boogers?Should we include boogers?
我很高兴我们在做这个
I'm happy we're doing this.
比起延长某人的肌腱,我更愿意干这个
I'd much rather do this than lengthensome guy's tendon.
病人的头痛更严重了
Patient's headachesincreased.
医生扫描了他的头部,发现了一个肿瘤
Doc scanned his head,found a tumor.
你喜欢浪费你的时间?
You like wasting your time?
- 我正在学,- 学了干什么?
-I'm learning.-To do what?
重新考虑已经解决的病例,因为你不想面对现实世界吗?
Reconsider solved cases because you don't want to deal with the real world?
他正在把我们推向死胡同
He's pushingwhere there's nothing.
Cameron 你是一名杰出的医生
Cameron, you arean excellent doctor.
会有许多感激涕零的病人向你泣谢
You'll get lotsof tearful thank-yous from grateful patients.
我还没那么渴望感谢
Yeah, am I such a bitchfor wanting that?
得了吧 那又不坏,不过这不是我为什么在这里的原因
Well, it's not a bad thing.But it's not why I'm here.
我得到了这个向 House 学习的机会
I took this fellowshipto learn from house.
他在教你怎样成为一个受虐狂
He's teaching youto be a masochist.
把干眼症写上白板
Dry eyes goes on the board.
在8年里 记录到214种症状,多种重复出现
in eight years, the patient experienced 214 symptoms, many of them repeating.
有没有什么模式?
Any patterns?
发热伴发尿频可能意味着前列腺炎
fever plus frequent urination could mean prostatitis.
或者是尿道感染
Or a urinary tract infection.
- 白细胞计数正常,- 无感染
-White count was normal.-No infection.
如果再加上疼痛 发热
if you add pain into the mix, fever,
尿频可能意味着肾有问题
frequent urination could indicate a kidney problem.
我喜欢这个想法
I like it.
不会的 肌酐和尿素氮都很正常
No.Creatinine and bunwere both normal.
不是说肾 是说疼痛
Not the kidney part.The pain part.
腹部疼痛加上那些症状可能就是胰腺囊肿
Abdominal pain plus all that stuff could equal pancreatic cysts.
漂亮 你们成功找出了一个,他从没有过的症状
perfect.You've managed to pick the one symptom he never had.
腹部疼痛
Abdominal pain.
那是白板上的第一个症状 咕噜
It's the first symptomon the board.Grunt.
咕噜又不能确诊为腹部疼痛
Grunting isn't pathognomonic for abdominal pain.
不
No.
传统的标志性症状是横膈膜的压缩
The traditionaldiagnostic marker is compression of the diaphragm
和喉部的震动 发出我们能听见的声音
and vibration of the larynx, leading to the audible sound.
"我感到腹部好痛"
"I have a painin my abdomen.
Richard 的症状是从8年的,病例里面精选出来的
"richard's symptoms are culled from eight yearsof medical history.
没有模式 这些只是8年间随机的,个体的病例
They're not patterned.These are random, individual events over time.
疾病有潜伏期
Illnesses haveincubation periods.
做个上呼吸道超声内镜检查
Do an upper endoscopic ultrasound.
他的咽喉会被毁掉的
his throat will collapse.
他颈部肌肉退化,无法承受这种程度的检查
Muscle degenerationin his neck won't tolerate the scope.
那可是个自动软管
It's an automatic trach.
听你们说他好像是个残疾人
You're talking about himlike he's an invalid.
我们没啥感觉
We're insensitive.
他淌口水吗? 他能直起自己的脖子吗?
Does he drool?Can he hold his neck straight?
他吃东西时呛吗?
Does he chokeon his food?
他脖子没问题 他的咽喉不会被毁掉的
His neck's fine.His throat'snot gonna collapse.
Cameron 去征得他妻子的同意
Cameron, get consentfrom the wife.
张嘴
Open.
我需要你做吞咽动作
I need you to swallow.
抱歉
Sorry about that.
开始
Here we go.
经过食道括约肌到达胃腔
Passing through the loweresophageal sphincter,,into the antrum of the stomach.
胰腺的后部
There's the tail of the pancreas.
没有病变
Looks clean.
向中间移动 胰腺的中部和头部也无病变
Moving medially,the body and the headof,the pancreas look clean--
拿出来
get it out.Get it out.
卡住了 动不了
It's stuck.I can't move it.
他喉咙塌陷了
His throat's collapsed.
心跳呼吸都成问题 情况紧急
Vitals are all overthe place.We're losing him.
切开
I'm cutting.
插入导管 用内窥镜法移出了探针,他才恢复呼吸
We trached him,endoscopicallyremoved the probe,,and he's breathing again.
总体来说 好主意
So,all in all,great idea.
在世界末日前观察到胰腺了吗?
Did you get a lookat the pancreas,before the world ended?
没有病变
It was clean.
说明除非你阻拦 他明天就能出院
Which means,barring anything else,,meaning you,he can go home tomorrow.
他差点死了 怎么能放他走?
This man nearly died.How can you discharge him?
我们的预测导致他喉咙塌陷
His throat collapsed becauseof what we predicted.
戳喉咙 肌肉会收缩 这是痉挛
you stick something down someone's throat,,they gag.Spasm.
他就是如此 用了半小时才取出探针
Which he did.It took us a half an hourto get that thing out.
除非病人的喉咙被镇静了
Except our patient's throatwas sedated.
大脑应该发送信号不做出反应
Which means the brainshould have sent,a signal in not to do anything.
可能会是癌症
This could be cancer.
或是异常的神经退化 甚至是新型--
Or some bizarre neurodegeneration.Even a new typeof vacular--
别说了
stop it.
你乐在其中
You're enjoying this.
我觉得有趣
I find it interesting.
你是对的 这才有趣,如果你错了 这么折磨他就只是取悦你
It's interestingonly if you're right.If you're wrong,we're torturing this guy to amuse you.
半小时取出探针?
Half hourto remove the probe?
House.
House
这不是痉挛
It's not a spasm.
他的喉咙不是塌陷 而是紧锁了
His throat didn't collapse.It locked down.
大脑协调身体的每块肌肉同时舒张或收缩
Brain is supposed to tell every muscle in,the body to relax and contract at the same time.
这块肌肉只是收缩,说明有一个大脑信号没有传送到
This muscle was onlycontracting,which means,a signal from thebrain was not getting through.
他大脑没有损伤 不会干扰指令
there are no lesions  his brain.Nothing to interruptany orders.
一根电路坏损就能导致
All it takes is one wire down.
没有证据哪根电路坏了
You have no evidenceof any wires down.
脑膜中有微小肿瘤,瞬时就窒息而死
A few microtumorson the meninges,,suddenly you're chokingto death.
你要查看他大脑皮层?
You wanna lookat the lining of his brain?
为了查看还得泵入大量造影剂--
the amount of contrast material,you'd need to pump up there just to see--
他会脑出血
he'll bleed into his brain.
- 不 他不会,-  那样就不好玩了
- No,he won'T.- Because that wouldn'tbe interesting.
你自己去请求家属同意吧
You can get permissionthis time.
大脑被嵌套在袋中 称作脑膜
The brain is enclosedin a sack,called the meninges.
难道癌症复发了?
Does this meanthe cancer's back?
不 不
No,no,no,no.
House.
House
如果发现是癌症
If we found cancer,
也不是原先的 而是新的癌症
it wouldn't bethe original cancer.It'd be new.
然后? 又是手术 化疗?
So what?More surgery?,More radiation?
情况也不至于最坏
Might not bethe worst thing.
如果不是旧病 也许可以医治
If this isn'tjust ancient history,,maybe it's somethingwe can correct.
甚至能挽救回一些大脑功能
Might even get some brain function back.
他会变好一点?
He could get better?
不
No.
他若能听懂你说话 该多好
But understanding whatyou're,saying would be nice.
说不定你们能想办法交流
Maybe you can figure outways to communicate.
幸好他对你说话了
Thank god he spoketo you.
McneiL女士
Mrs.McneiL.
检查风险很高
The test to do this is very risky.
他会死
He could die.
他现在生不如死
He's already dead.
Chase 慢点
chase,  go slow
已经注入脊髓腔
already injected into spinal canal
下一站 大脑
next stop is brain
造影剂进入第4脑室
contrast material entering into,the fourth ventricle.
室壁无出血
No parietal bleeds.
血压高 但能控制住
Blood pressure's high.But it's holding.
脑膜完整 无出血
meninges are intact.No bleeding.
天
Oh,god.
Foreman 过来看
Foreman,get in here.
你很幸运 他没有死
you are lucky he didn't die
我幸运? 是他没死
I'm lucky? he is the one who didn'y die
说过会有出血
we told you he had haemorrhage
你们说他会脑出血 不是耳出血
you told me he bleed into his brain,not out of his ear
你得停止
gotta drop this
错过了什么
I'm missing something
做了危险的检查 造成了损伤
we did a dangerous test,and something bad happened
如此而已
that's all this is
带我漫游他的脑子 Foreman
give me tour of the brain Foreman
从头游览这些扫描图 1998年
walk me through the scans
发生了什么
what happened
如果我脑子里长了厘米级的瘤子...
*******
不是这个
nothing
下一个 颞上部的斑点
next,spec on the superior temporal region
重新生长出的 良性
It's regrowth, it's benign
旁边的星状
*****
活检造成的疤痕组织
scar tissue from bioposy
House 没有什么斑点可疑,是外科医生挖掘他的头
House, every spec is not suspect,It's use of surgeon digging around his head
让他走吧
let him go
重新做血液检查
we do every blood test he's ever had
再次扫描他的头
re-scan his head
不
no
他已经受伤病折磨了8年,我不会帮你作孽
he's in sick in suffering for 8 years,and I'm not gonna helping make it worse
不会帮你寻乐子
I'm not gonna help you make interesting
没事 Foreman对这比你在行
That's okay.Foreman's better at that stuffthan you are.
在他枕骨和下丘脑处切开5毫米
We need 5-millimeter cuts through,the occipitaland hypothalamic regions.
不
No.
几毫米?
How many millimeters?
我能帮他
I can help him.
如此而已? 这就是你的论据?
This is it?,That's your argument?
很充分
Seems like a good one.
只要我稍微思考你是想帮他,你得取得全权委托书
If I thought for a secondyou wanted,to help him,you'd have carte blanche.
你这么做是为了好玩
You're doing thisbecause it's fun.
这医院里的人除了我的动机,就没别的好谈论了?
Does nobodyin this hospital have,anything betterto talk about than my motives?
我的动机和案例没关系
My motives have nothing to dowith the case.
你的动机和判断息息相关
Your motives have everythingto,do with your judgment.
这么多年来第一次 我体内没有了鸦片
For the first time in years,,I've got no opiates in my body.
你质疑我的判断
Now you question my judgment.
一年有24次 你闯进我办公室,叫嚣着要帮谁
24 times a year you comestorming into my office,,spouting that you can help someone.
可是你从来不这么说
Only you never saythose words.
你会嚷嚷诸如
You say something like,
"他的胰腺要爆炸了 因为大脑着了火"
"his pancreas is gonna explodebecause,his brain is on fire."
你基于医学理由 而不是泛泛而谈
You come here with medicine,,not with platitudes.
我不想说细节 惹你乏味
I didn't want to bore youwith the details.
根本没有细节
There are no details.
你只有个直觉
You have a hunch.
House 你不依靠直觉
House,you don't use hunches.
你总是有理由的
You always have reasons.
医院不是因你的突发奇想而生存,很抱歉
This hospital doesn't exist for your whims.I'm sorry.
明早7点 就让你的病人出院
As of 7:00 A.M. Tomorrow morning,,I'm sending your patient home.
回答是不
The answer is no.
Cuddy在你离开后30秒就打电话来,说你钻牛角尖
Cuddy called 30 secondsafter you left,and said you'd tryan end around.
我的腿疼了
My leg hurt.
厉害吗?
How bad?
疼到我对你说
Enough that I'mtelling you.
消失了吗?
Did it go away?
疼了一小会
Ached for a while.
手术后 那里第一次有感觉
First time I've felt anythingthere,since the surgery.
但是消失了
But it went away.
肌肉痛 有些抽筋
It was muscular.There was some cramping.
你笑什么?
What are you smiling about?
你40老几了 天知道你一天跑了几英里
You're 40-somethingyears old. You've been,running god knows how many miles a day.
从滑板上摔下100次 有疼痛你居然会震惊
Fallen 100 tim off that skateboard,,and you're shocked to have some soreness?
给我开个处方
Just give mea prescription.
维柯丁?
For vicodin?
House 一般人关节痛或是抽筋,就敷个冰袋 或吃布洛芬
House,people getaching joints,cramps,,they put onan ice pack.They take some ibuprofen.
我知道中年的疼痛怎么回事
I know what the pangsof middle age feel like.
不 你不知道
No,you don'T.
自从中年起,你每隔5分钟就吞一次止疼药
Because you've been stuffingvicodin every,five minutes since you turned middle-age.
手术没起作用
The surgery didn't work.
不要戏弄我
Don't play me.
哦 你以为我耍诡计?
Oh,you thinkthis is a scam?
我认为你想博取我的同情,帮你说服Cuddy或是给你药
I think you want meto feel sorry for you and either,do the end around on cuddy or give you the drugs.
哪一样 都让你飘飘欲仙
Either way,you get the highyou,think you need.
House 手术起作用了 你没事
House,your surgery worked.You're fine.
只是要花点时间好起来
It's just gonna take timefor,it to feel good.
室周系统感受到免疫反应,早期阶段释放出的细胞因子
The circumventricular systemsenses cytokines,released in the early stagesof the immune response.
但神经核团释放出的前列腺素,上调了下丘脑体温控制点
But cvos releases prostaglandinsthat,reset the hypothalamic set point upward,
除非用退烧药来治疗
unless it's countered by anti-pyretic therapy.
是的 他脑子着火了
So yeah,his brainis on fire.
试图自杀并不是自杀
The suicide attempt was not a suicide attempt.
他把轮椅开进泳池 因为不能控制体温
He drove that wheelchairinto the pool,because he couldn't regulatehis body temperature.
他得了下丘脑功能失调
He had hypothalamicdysregulation.
你发现了这...
And you discovered this...
当你步入
when you stepped into the...
大学的泳池?
university pool?
喷泉
Fountain.
- 我能治好他,- 治好他
- I can cure him.- Cure him.
就算喷泉给出了指示,治疗下丘脑调节紊乱也不能让大脑重启
Even if the fountainproved anything,fixing,hypothalamicdysregulation isn't gonna regenerate brain.
不能 除非他下丘脑的疤痕组织
No,but if the scar tissueon his hypothalamus
挤压了垂体 关闭了肾上腺
is restingagainst the pituitary,,the adrenals would shut down.
阿狄森氏病
Addison's disease.
从MRI你没看到任何疤痕组织,他的CT检测--
You didn't see anyscar tissue on his mri.His ct scans--
- 他的大脑还有功能,- 他的体温正常
- his brain is functional.- His temperature's normal.
他的下丘脑和垂体都没问题
There is nothing wrong with his,hypothalamusor his pituitary.
我能让他走路 让他说话
I can make him walk.I can make him talk.
你一身臭汗 所以才能冒出这样的瞎猜
This is a wild guess that came,to youbecause you were sweating.
注射可的松
Inject him with cortisol.
这个人可以再次跟妻子欢好,再次拥抱儿子
The guy'll have sexwith his wife again.He'll hug his kid again.
但愿他是用这种组合
Hopefully that'sthe combination he was using.
否则我就救了一个恋童癖
Be a shameif I cured a pedophile.
你在微笑 不是好兆头
You're smiling.That's a bad sign.
你吃药了
You're high.
我说了过去3个月我都没沾药
I told you I haven't hadanything,in three months.
你一兴奋就这样
This is as highas you get.
你把病例用一个无根据的理论包装
A theory that ties your case up,in a neat little bow.
却拿不出一点证据
But you don't have a lickof,substantiating proof.
你的决定不合理
Your decisiondoesn't make any sense.
注射可的松没有风险,就算我错了 有什么大不了
There is no risk to a cortisol injection.If I'm wrong,big deal.
他像往常一样 作为一个植物人回家,但如果我是对的
He goes home a vegetable,like he already is.But if I'm right--
这不是好与坏的风险权衡
this is not about downsidesor,risk management.
重要的是让你懂得,如何接受"不"这个词
It is a big deal for youto,understand the word no.
对不起 House
I'm sorry,house.
他要出院了
He's on his wayout of here.
我以为你会窜下楼去,在他脖子上扎一针可的松
Figured you'd beon your scooter racing down the,halls to stab the patient in the neckwith cortisol.
她说"不"是对的
She was right to say no.
我自认为正确的 其实没有客观理由
I had no objective reason to,thinkthat I was right.
只是解谜
Just needed the puzzle.
稍等
Hold on a sec.
没事吧?
Is everything all right?
我忘了一点事情
Yeah,it's just somethingI forgot.
什么?
What's that?
可的松
This is cortisol.
抗感染
And it's to fight infection.
帮我压一下
Wanna hold onto that?
贴一块纱布
Put a bandage on it.
他没事吧?
Let's see.Is he okay?
没事
Yes.
我们能走了吗?
Can we go now?
可以走了
You can go.
借过
Excuse me.
Richard.Richard.
爸 你没事吧
Dad,you okay?
Richard?
Richard!,Richard!
你站起来了
You're standing.
谢谢
Thank you.
他站起来了
he got up.
- 我得告诉House,- 不
- I have to go tell house.- No.
Cuddy.
不能告诉他
You can't tell him.
当然要说 他是对的
I have to tell him.He was right.
为什么这么做?
Why did you do it?
为什么你觉得他有可能对?
Why did you thinkhe might be right?
因为他是House
Because he's house.
医学角度 你根据什么判断他是对的
Medically.What made you thinkhe was right?
- 没根据,- 他运气好
- Nothing.- He got lucky.
只能从运气解释
That's all that happened.
跟他说"不"对他是好事
Telling him nowas a good thing.
因为下次 他不会这么好运,他会杀死某人
Because next time,he won't get lucky.He'll kill someone.
他对了 并不表明他没错
Just becausehe was right doesn't,meanhe wasn't wrong.
我每天都见他
I see him every day.
不能就这么...
I can't just...
人人都撒谎
everybody lies.